Guide to the Richard St. John Papers, 1972-2020 SC.2020.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Poetry by decade, 1972-2019; VII.
  - Poetry from the 2000s, 2000-2020; 5.
    - "Acolytes (A Found Poem)", 2003 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - "A Toast", 2003 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - "Seven Tragic Deaths – February 1, 2003" (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - "AIDS Documentary on Video TV," correspondence about poem, 2003-2007 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - "Restaurant Conversation–Virginia, 2003" (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Untitled drafts, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - "Memorial Day Flags", 2004 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - "UN Report, 2003", 2004 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - "Between", 2004-2007 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - "Rereading, in Maine", 2005 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - "Day Lilies", 2005 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - "Framing", 2005 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - "Unemployed, I Converse with Milton", 2006 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - "Where We Live: A Letter", 2006 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - "The Situation in Sudan", 2006 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - "Flying Horse, Kung Dynasty", 2006 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - "Watching the Televangelists, I Fall into a Funk," correspondence about poem, 2006-2007 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - "Her Signature", 2006 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - "Still," correspondence about poem, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - "Craft Booth at the Three Rivers Arts Festival", 2006 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - "The New Logos," correspondence about poem, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - "Unseen", 2007-2018 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - "Self-Portrait at 55", 2007-2010 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - "Power and the Trees", 2007 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - "Why It's an Epic", 2007 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - "A Tear is an Intellectual Thing", 2008 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - "Paradife Lofts", 2008 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - "Our Lady of Fatima Oversees the Paving Operation", 2008 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - "Pulse", 2008 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - "At the Psychiatrist's Office", 2008 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - "Lullaby", 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - "The Old Innkeeper Fixes a Porch Light While his Wife gets chemotherapy", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - "Reader", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - "Sunflower", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - "Dark Matter", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - "Like This", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - "Needle, Haystack, Blood", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Email correspondence, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - "How My Sunday School Pals Led Me Astray", 2009-2019 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - "Lost", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - "Late, Again", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - "Reverberations", 2009-2020 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - "Those are Pearls that Were His Eyes", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - "Cat Scan", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - "Celebrity Apprentice: Time-Travel Edition", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - "The Field", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - "Stockroom", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - "Evidence", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - "Green Ice", 2009 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - "Wide Circumference: A Sequence," correspondence about poem, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Poetry from the 2010s, 2010-2019; 4.
    This subseries includes drafts of poetry from the 2010s. These drafts, referred to by the author as "discarded materials," are unpublished.
    - "Wilderness Encounter", 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Dandelions", 2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "Bird Songs", 2010 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "Then and Now", 2010 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Enhanced Interrogation", 2010 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "The Mark", 2010 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Frac You", 2010 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Sleep," correspondence about poem, 2011-2018 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Weary", 2011 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Anniversary", 2011 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "Exchange, 1954", 2011 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Quake", 2012 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "New Year's Day", 2012 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Useless Winter, the Unemployed," correspondence about poem, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Getting the Healing Right", 2012 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "God Bless America", 2012 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "How It All Started," correspondence about poem, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Jeweled Net", 2015-2016 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Unconfirmed Report", 2012-2015 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Election Day, 2016" (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "Longing for Paradise", 2016 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - "The Long Shower", 2016 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "Tattoo," correspondence about poem, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - "Saleh, Aleppo 2016" (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "Today's News", 2017 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - "Shoes", 2017 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "The Flag", 2018 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - "After a Year of Bad News, I Learn, Still Worse, That Trump Will Appoint a 2nd Supreme Court Justice", 2018 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "The Basilisk", 2019 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Poetry published in periodicals, 1982-2015; VIII.
  This series contains St. John's published works featured in newspapers and literary magazines. Oversized materials that appear in this series can be found in Oversize 5.
  - Observing Natural History in Western Pennsylvania, "The Bird in Our Garage", undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 5 AM, "Heidegger's Pear", 2003 (Oversize 5, Folder 8)
  - Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, "Upstate New York, In Difficult Times", 2007 (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh City Paper, "Two Stories", 2006 (Oversize 5, Folder 7)
  - Along These Rivers, excerpt from "Christmas Requiem", 2008 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Poet Lore, Review of The Pure Inconstancy of Grace, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - The Sewanee Review, "A Largo", 2000 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - The International Poetry Forum, Fortieth Anniversary event program, "Many, Ever-Changing Lights, A Review of W.S. Merwin", 2006-2007 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Meridian Anthology of Contemporary Poetry, "Circling Walden Pond" "Meditation for a Wedding", 2006 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - The Comstock Review, "From the Plate", 2004 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Natural Language: Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh Sunday Poetry and Reading Series Anthology, "A Largo", 2010 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Paper Street, "The Sainthood of St. Julian", 2004 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Carolina Quarterly, "Epiphany at the Dennis Public Dump", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - HEArt, "L 'Anima Semplicetta", 2000 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - yawp, "Photographs, Circa the Present" "The Bird in Our Garage" "Birdwatching Without Binoculars", 2000 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - The Fourth River, Issue 9, "Pluto 1" "Pluto 2" "Pluto 3", 2012 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Saint Katherine Review, Volume 1, Number 4, "Abhorrent Things", undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - U.S. 1 Worksheets, Volume 59, "Penelope in Firelight", 2014 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Poet Lore, Volume 98, Number ¾, "The Sparrows of Bahrain" "Sojourn in the City of Absence", 2003 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - NewPeople, "L 'Anima Semplicetta", 2000 (Oversize 5, Folder 9)
  - 5 AM, Issue 30, "'The Garden Will Come to You' / A Conversation with Frank X Gaspar" "LOST TURTLE", 2009 (Oversize 5, Folder 10)
  - NewPeople, Volume 39, Number 3, "Reading Shaw's Play, St. Joan at the Solstice, on a Greyhound, Heading Home", 2009 (Oversize 5, Folder 11)
  - Pittsburgh City Paper, Volume 25, Issue 20, Book Review of Each Perfected Name, 2015 (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh City Paper, Volume 19, Issue 38, "I Write to the G-20 Leaders in Advance of Their Pittsburgh Summit", 2009 (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, "Sparrow in the Supermarket", 2006 (Oversize 5, Folder 12)
  - Rune Literary Journal, "Vita Nuova," (errors in printed version), 2013 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Chautauqua: Nature and the Natural World, Issue 8, "Eclipse", 2011 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - The Fourth River, Issue 5, "A Blessing in Baltimore", 2008 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Audio-Visual Materials, 1999-2000; IX.
  This series includes photography of St. John's trip to Walden Pond in Massachusetts along with a cassette tape recording of St. John at a radio station poetry reading.
  - WYEP "Prosody" Reading, cassette tape, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Walden Pond, MA (22 Photographic Prints), 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 51)